{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "This case was originally filed against H.G. Cochrane who retired soon after. The winner of this case was forced to sit for a second trial during which he was represented by Fred Turner. This case overturned the “special circumstances” requirement written in Betts v. Brady. In this case, Abe Fortas argued on the behalf of a defendant who had broken into a Florida pool hall. The public defender system was expanded as a result of, for ten points, what case that expanded the accused’s right to an attorney to states.",
      "answer": [
        "Gideon v. Wainwright",
        "either underlined name"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Five of these structures were based on the island of Kneiphof [neep-hof], where Immanuel Kant is buried, but two of the five were destroyed during World War II bombing raids. These structures, which spanned the Pregel River, were the subject of a popular thought problem that was solved in 1736 by a clever, early use of graph theory. For ten points, name this set of walkways in a Prussian city, now the Russian city of Kaliningrad, that were famously studied by Leonhard Euler [oiler].",
      "answer": "Seven Bridges of K¨onigsberg"
    },
    {
      "question": "This battle’s loser boasted that “an arm when cut off cannot grow again, but a shorn beard will.” Marco Bragadin was flayed alive after buying time for this battle’s winning side to assemble a fleet. This battle was prompted by the siege of Famagusta and the loss of one participant’s colony of Cyprus. Miguel Cervantes lost an arm fighting under Don Juan of Austria in this battle, the last great engagement between galleys. For ten points, identify this naval victory for the Holy League over the Ottomans in 1571.",
      "answer": "Battle of Lepanto"
    },
    {
      "question": "Peter Malkin’s memoirs about this event inspired a 2018 film starring Ben Kingsley as this event’s subject and also featuring Michael Aronov as Zvi Aharoni. During this event, a team led by Rafi Eitan raided a home on Garibaldi Street. This event, the subject of the film Operation Finale, resulted in agents of Mossad drugging a man for his flight out of Argentina in May 1960. For ten points, name this event that allowed a Nazi to be put on trial in Israel.",
      "answer": [
        "Mossad/Israel’s capture or synonyms of Adolf Eichmann",
        "equivalents"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "JamesMartinEderrevolutionizedthisindustryatthe“LaManuelita”haciendawithsteampower.The Mascate War was fought between Portuguese merchants and landowners of this industry in Pernambuco. John Drax used slave labor to develop this industry in Barbados, which later utilized Benjamin Delessert’s method of extracting this industry’s commodity from beet roots. For ten points, name this industry central to the Caribbean colonies, products from which were used to make rum and molasses.",
      "answer": "sugarcane industry"
    },
    {
      "question": "FollowersofthismanbrokeintothehouseofRebeccaVaughanandkilledwhilesheprayed.Afterbeing found hiding among the Nottoway by Benjamin Phipps, this man asked “Was Christ not crucified?” The blueish-green appearance of the Sun, possibly caused by an eruption of Mount St. Helens, was interpreted by this man as a message from God to begin one event. Thomas Gray recorded the “confessions” of this man who may have ordered his followers to “kill all the white people.” For ten points, name this slave who led an 1831 rebellion in Southampton County, Virginia.",
      "answer": "Nat Turner"
    },
    {
      "question": "During this conflict, one side’s declaration that they were preparing the Samson Option prompted the United States to provide aid in Operation Nickel Grass. This conflict commenced with a surprise attack in Operation Badr on the Bar Lev Line. Henry Kissinger’s shuttle diplomacy helped bring an end to this conflict, the failure to prevent which led Golda Meir to resign. For ten points, name this conflict in which Arab forces surprised Israel on the Day of Atonement.",
      "answer": "Yom Kippur War"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man’s first term as prime minister ended after Daniel O’Connell allied with Lord Melbourne to block any law this man proposed. This man sparked the Bedchamber Crisis and penned the Tamworth Manifesto, one of the cornerstones of the Conservative Party. This man resigned after siding with the opposition to repeal the Corn Laws in the wake of the Irish Potato Famine. For ten points, identify this British prime minister who founded the London Metropolitan Police Force.",
      "answer": "Robert Peel"
    },
    {
      "question": "Steve Bales accepted an award for his role in this mission for saying “Go” when he could have said “Stop” or “Wait.” A planned speech in case this mission failed opens with “Fate has ordained” that men who went to “explore in peace” will now “rest in peace.” After completing a landing procedure in this mission, its participants radioed Houston to say “The Eagle has landed.” For ten points, name this mission in which Neil Armstrong said “That’s one small step for man” after landing on the moon.",
      "answer": "Apollo 11"
    },
    {
      "question": "A work by this composer was adapted from the last two tableau of his posthumously published Press Celebrations Music. The Biafran national anthem was adapted from a melody by this composer, as was the hymn Be Still, My Soul. This composer of seven symphonies left his final one, in C major, unfinished. One of this composer’s works was censored during his country’s independence movement from Russia at the start of the 20th century. For ten points, name this composer of Finlandia.",
      "answer": "Jean Sibelius"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "One side in this trial was represented by Samuel Phillips who was opposed by Milton Joseph Cunningham, a man arrested during Reconstruction for restoring white supremacy. Henry Billings Brown reasoned that the matters of “health, safety, and morals” belong to the state government in this majority decision for this case. The lone dissent in this case argued that “our constitution is color-blind.” A violation of Louisiana’s Separate Car Act prompted, for ten points, what case which created the doctrine of “separate but equal?”",
        "answer": "Plessy v. Ferguson"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The lone dissent in Plessy v. Ferguson came from this Justice who, due to his penchant for performing such actions, was nicknamed “The Great Dissenter.”",
        "answer": "John Marshall Harlan"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "One work builds on Joan Riviere’s comment that a variant of this word is a “masquerade,” claiming that this word is open to “resignification” because this word’s definition is performative and the category this word implies is invalid. In another work, one author argues that this word is defined as a dialectic “Other” and quipped, “one is not born, but becomes” this word. For ten points, name this word at the center of Judith Butler’s Gender Trouble and Simone de Beauvoir’s The Second Sex.",
        "answer": "“woman”"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Gender Trouble also engages what thinker’s History of Sexuality, which examines historical discourse to argue that sex is a social construct and subject to societal forms of power?",
        "answer": "Michel Foucault"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Prior warning of this event was given by a chauffeur nicknamed Jean-Pierre. The Batwa people are often called the “forgotten victims” of this event, which was spurred by propaganda from the RTLM radio station. Romeo Dallaire’s UNAMIR failed to prevent this event, which began after the death of President Habyarimana. This event was mainly perpetuated by the Interahamwe militia and came to an end when RPF forces captured Kigali. For ten points, name this 1994 genocide of Tutsis by Hutus.",
        "answer": "Rwandan Genocide"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This current President of Rwanda commanded the RPF forces which ended the genocide.",
        "answer": "Paul Kagame"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The windows of the Althing were smashed during protests against this organization, which needed Iceland to fill the GIUK gap. The Lemnitzer-Ailleret agreements outlined how the French army could reenterthisorganizationevenafterdeGaullewithdrewfromitin1966.Thisorganizationintervenedinthe Bosnian War by enforcing Operation Deny Flight. For ten points, name this mutual defense organization formed after World War II with the primary goal of countering the USSR.",
        "answer": [
          "NATO or North Atlantic Treaty Organization",
          "North Atlantic Alliance"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "NATO’s Article 5 commits signatories to this doctrine, which states that an attack on one member state is treated as an attack on every member state.",
        "answer": "collective security or collective defense"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A communist party leader from this modern country, Edvard Kadelj, was accidentally shot by Jovan Veselinov, who was aiming at a wild boar. This country’s DEMOS party helped form its first government, after which it declared independence, leading to the Brioni Agreement after winning the Ten Day War and beginning a general breakup of a Balkan conglomerate state. The historical region of Carniola is the site of, for ten points, what former Yugoslav republic’s capital of Ljubljana?",
        "answer": "Slovenia"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Slovenia’s small Adriatic littoral borders what northeastern Italian port city that was ceded to Italy via the 1975 Treaty of Osimo?",
        "answer": "Trieste"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This author’s disgust at Ivan Ivanov’s murder by Sergei Nechaev spurred him to attack nihilism in a work centered on the morally dubious Nikolai Stavrogin in which Shatov is murdered by Pyotr Stepanovich. This author of Demons wrote a work where Sonya helps the main character wrestle with the morality of his actions and follows him to Siberia after he confesses to the theft and murder of an elderly pawn broker. Raskolnikov features in, for ten points, what author’s Crime and Punishment?",
        "answer": "Fyodor Dostoevsky"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Dostoevsky included a parable in this larger work where Jesus is arrested by the Grand Inquisitor and is told that humanity can’t handle the freedom given to it by Jesus.",
        "answer": "The Brothers Karamazov"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "These structures were extensively studied at the Dahshur site, which includes a “bent” variant of these structures as the result of a failed attempt to create smoothed sides. These structures were created by combining multiple mastabas. The earliest example of these structures held Djoser’s body and was constructed by Imhotep, while another three were commissioned by Khafre, Khufu, and Menkaure. For ten points, identify these structures that are located in Giza as a burial place for pharaohs.",
        "answer": "pyramids"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Pyramids were connected to valley temples or mortuary temples by these structures, which were usually long elevated walkways.",
        "answer": "causeways"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "To facilitate this event, a secret communication channel called “Private Blank Check” was set-up by two participants. Medhi Hasehmi may have been executed due to his role in this event, as he was arrested soon after leaking information to Ash-Shiraa. Fawn Hall defended herself by saying “We shred everything” after being implicated in this scandal. John Poindexter resigned as National Security Adviser due to this scandal. For ten points, name this Reagan-era scandal in which weapons were sold to a Middle Eastern country in order to fund a Nicaraguan rebel group.",
        "answer": "Iran-Contra affair"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Fawn Hall was the secretary of this Lieutenant Colonel who was sentenced to a three year suspended sentence after being found guilty of three felonies.",
        "answer": "Oliver North"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Robert Kennedy",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Cabinet position he held under his brother, the head of the Justice Department.",
          "answer": "Attorney General"
        },
        {
          "question": "President of the Teamsters who quarreled with RFK and disappeared in 1975.",
          "answer": "James “Jimmy” Hoffa"
        },
        {
          "question": "Midwest state capital where he gave an impropmtu speech after the assassination of Martin Luther King.",
          "answer": "Indianapolis"
        },
        {
          "question": "State where he was shot and killed after campaigning in its Democratic primary.",
          "answer": "California"
        },
        {
          "question": "Palestinian man who shot him.",
          "answer": "Sirhan Sirhan"
        },
        {
          "question": "Minnesota senator who finished second in that primary, then remarked Kennedy “brought [the shooting] on himself.”",
          "answer": "Eugene McCarthy"
        },
        {
          "question": "Foreign city where Kennedy gave the 1966 Day of Affirmation speech.",
          "answer": "Cape Town"
        },
        {
          "question": "Biographer who campaigned for RFK after writing the JFK book A Thousand Days.",
          "answer": "Arthur Schlesinger"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Mahatma Gandhi",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Religion followed by Gandhi and his assassin, the majority religion in India.",
          "answer": "Hinduism"
        },
        {
          "question": "Muslim-majority country whose rivalry with India led Gandhi’s assassin to act.",
          "answer": "Pakistan"
        },
        {
          "question": "Indian Prime Minister who lamented “the light has gone out of our lives” after Gandhi’s death.",
          "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru"
        },
        {
          "question": "Man who shot and killed Gandhi.",
          "answer": "Nathuram Godse"
        },
        {
          "question": "Spiritual caste, the highest of the four classes, into which Gandhi’s assassin was born.",
          "answer": "Brahmin"
        },
        {
          "question": "House where Gandhi was assassinated; it is now a museum.",
          "answer": "Birla House"
        },
        {
          "question": "Former Mughal palace where Gandhi’s assassin was put on trial.",
          "answer": "Red Fort or Lal Qila"
        },
        {
          "question": "Co-conspirator who helped buy the gun and was also hanged for his role in Gandhi’s assassination.",
          "answer": "Narayan Apte"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Other Assassinations",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Habsburg Archduke, husband of Sophie, whose killing helped spark World War I.",
          "answer": "Archduke Franz Ferdinand"
        },
        {
          "question": "Russian mystic who was drugged, shot, and dumped in a river in 1916.",
          "answer": "Grigori Rasputin"
        },
        {
          "question": "Nazi attack, known as the “Night of Broken Glass,” that followed the assassination of Ernst vom Rath.",
          "answer": "Kristallnacht"
        },
        {
          "question": "Former KGB officer who was poisoned with polonium-210 in England in 2006.",
          "answer": "Alexander Litvinenko"
        },
        {
          "question": "Last Viceroy of India, who was killed by an Irish bomb on his boat in 1979.",
          "answer": "Louis Mountbatten, Earl Mountbatten"
        },
        {
          "question": "Only British Prime Minister to be assassinated.",
          "answer": "Spencer Perceval"
        },
        {
          "question": "Chair of the Wannsee Conference, a Nazi who was ambushed in his car by Czech soldiers.",
          "answer": "Reinhard Heydrich"
        },
        {
          "question": "Film director killed in 2004 for working with Ayaan Hirsi Ali on the film Submission.",
          "answer": "Theo van Gogh"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This political party’s official ideology of “integral humanism” was developed in the 1960s. This party has historically advocated for the abrogation of Article 370. This organization and the VHP were responsible for the demolition of a (20 pts)",
        "mosque in 1992 located in Ayodhya. This party’s current leader demonetized his country’s high-denomination banknotes in 2016 and served as Chief Minister of (10 pts)",
        "Gujarat during 2002 anti-Muslim riots. For ten points, name this Hindu nationalist party led by Narendra Modi, a frequent rival to the Indian National Congress Party."
      ],
      "answer": "Bharata Janata Party"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In the aftermath of this event, Roswell Mason ordered Philip Sheridan to declare martial law. A warehouse constructed by Gurdon (20 pts)",
        "Hubbard to supply Fort Dearborn with meat was destroyed in this event. This event resulted in the destruction of the luxurious Palmer House which had opened just 13 days prior. Only seven (10 pts)",
        "buildings survived in the area affected by this event, including the city’s water tower. Mrs O’Learly’s cow is incorrectly claimed to be the cause of, for ten points, what 1871 disaster that heavily damaged a large Illinois city?"
      ],
      "answer": "Great Chicago Fire"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In one of this artist’s unfinished works, George Sand sat next to Chopin at a piano. One of this artist’s works depicts Jacob wrestling with the angel and is frescoed on a wall next to this artist’s Heliodorus Chased from the Temple in the (20 pts)",
        "Church of Saint-Sulpice. This artist was inspired by Gericault’s Raft of the Medusa in a work where tormented souls attack a vessel carrying a red-hooded figure and (10 pts)",
        "Virgil, the Barque of Dante. In this artist’s best known work, a boy waves a pistol next to a woman carrying the French tricolor in the July Revolution. For ten points, name this artist of Liberty Leading the People."
      ],
      "answer": "Eug`ene Delacroix"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) While serving in the National Guard, this man agreed with Rafael Estrella to not intervene in a coup against Horatio Vasquez. This man’s regime was aided by the “Forty- Two” gang and the (20 pts)",
        "SIM secret police. This leader’s angered the Organization of American States after he ordered an assassination attempt on Romulo Betancourt. This leader ordered the killing of the (10 pts)",
        "Mirabal Sisters and the mass execution of Haitian immigrants in the Parsley Massacre. Nicknamed “The Chief”, for ten points, name this long-time dictator of the Dominican Republic."
      ],
      "answer": "Rafael Leonidas Trujillo"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The February Patent established this state’s Imperial Council, deputies to which were elected by a curiae system. An heir apparent to this state committed suicide along with Baroness Mary Vetsera in the (20 pts)",
        "Mayerling Incident. Ferenc Deak [dee-ack] and Gyula Andrassy were instrumental to establishing this state in the 1867 (10 pts)",
        "Ausgleich agreement. The Allied Powers dissolved this state with the separate treaties of Saint-Germain-en-Laye and Trianon. For ten points, name this dual monarchy whose 1914 declaration of war against Serbia triggered the First World War."
      ],
      "answer": "Austria-Hungary"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Seven men were beaten by police officers in Los Angeles in 1951 during an incident named for this day. In 1963, over 500 Cypriots were killed during an incident named for this day. Edmund the Martyr was (20 pts)",
        "anointed on this day, which was banned by Puritans in 1647. 40 days named for St. Martin of Tours precede this holiday, on which Charlemagne was (10 pts)",
        "crowned emperor in 800 AD. Charles Dickens contributed to the revival of this holiday in Britain with his novella about Ebenezer Scrooge. For 10 points, name this Christian holiday celebrating the birth of Christ."
      ],
      "answer": "Christmas"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man adopted Olive Risley after rumors of an affair between them grew. He served as Governor of New York during the trial of Alexander McLeod for his involvement with the (20 pts)",
        "Caroline affair. Lewis Powell injured this man during the 1865 assassination plot against Lincoln. He negotiated with (10 pts)",
        "Eduard Stoeckl to purchase an expanse of land deemed his “Folly” by detractors. For 10 points, name this Secretary of State under Abraham Lincoln who negotiated the Alaskan Purchase with Russia."
      ],
      "answer": "William H. Seward"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Charles Loyseau speculated that these people descended from conquering Franks and classified them into three categories in his Treatise on Orders. These people were called “of the (20 pts)",
        "robe” and “of the sword” depending on if they were administrators or served in the military. Wealthy merchants were able to become one of these people by purchasing (10 pts)",
        "venal offices. These people’s privileges included the right to wear a sword and exemption from direct land taxes. The Second Estate consisted of, for ten points, what non-common class of Ancien Regime French society?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "French nobility",
        "the Second Estate before mention,",
        "aristocracy,",
        "nobleman",
        "any variation on being noble"
      ]
    }
  ]
}